<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks on Michele Scipioni</title>
    <link>https://mscipio.github.io/talk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks on Michele Scipioni</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Michele Scipioni</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mscipio.github.io/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kinetic Compressive Sensing</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/talk/ieee-nss-mic-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/talk/ieee-nss-mic-2017/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
Parametric images provide insight into the spatial distribution of physiological parameters, but they are often extremely noisy, due to low SNR of tomographic data. Direct estimation from projections allows accurate noise modeling, improving the results of post-reconstruction fitting. We propose a method, which we name kinetic compressive sensing (KCS), based on a hierarchical Bayesian model and on a novel reconstruction algorithm, that encodes sparsity of kinetic parameters.
Methods
The model has three key components: the model of the acquisition system; the kinetic model; and a Markov Random Field with an L1-norm cost function, defined in kinetic parameters domain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kinetic compressive sensing: improving image reconstruction and parametric maps</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/talk/martinosopenhouse17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/talk/martinosopenhouse17/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
Parametric images provide insight into the spatial distribution of physiological parameters, but they are often extremely noisy, due to low SNR of tomographic data. Direct estimation from projections allows accurate noise modeling, improving the results of post-reconstruction fitting. We propose a method, which we name kinetic compressive sensing (KCS), based on a hierarchical Bayesian model and on a novel reconstruction algorithm, that encodes sparsity of kinetic parameters.
Methods
The model has three key components: the model of the acquisition system; the kinetic model; and a Markov Random Field with an L1-norm cost function, defined in kinetic parameters domain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Influence of Noise in Dynamic PET Direct Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/talk/medicon16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/talk/medicon16/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
In the present work a study is carried out in order to assess the efficiency of the direct reconstruction algorithms on noisy dynamic PET data. The study is performed via Monte Carlo simulations of a uniform cylindrical phantom whose emission values change in time according to a kinetic law. After generating the relevant projection data and properly adding the effects of different noise sources on them, the direct reconstruction and parametric estimation algorithm is applied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pharmacokinetic analysis of dynamic PET data: comparison between direct parametric reconstruction and conventional indirect voxel-based estimation</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/talk/emim16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/talk/emim16/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
Dynamic positron emission tomography (PET) studies allow to quantify tissue-specific biochemical properties. Conventional pharmacokinetic analysis requires the voxel-wise time activity curve fitting performed on a sequence of independently reconstructed PET images. Direct parametric reconstruction methods combine emission image reconstruction and kinetic modeling into a single formula, estimating parametric images directly from raw data. In the present work a comparison between the two pharmacokinetic analysis methods is performed on simulated and clinical brain 18F[FDG] PET data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>