<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Michele Scipioni</title>
    <link>https://mscipio.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Michele Scipioni</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Michele Scipioni</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mscipio.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Add comments to your Hugo-Academic blog in 10 minutes, using Utteranc.es</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/post/utterances-comment-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/post/utterances-comment-engine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://utteranc.es/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Utteranc.es&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a lightweigth comments widget, which allows you to use &lt;strong&gt;Github Issues&lt;/strong&gt; for blog comments. It&amp;rsquo;s open source, looks clean, comments are stored on Github, and even comes with a dark theme. Sure, you need to sign with Github, but that&amp;rsquo;s fine since most coders already have an account.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calling Matlab (custom) functions from Python</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/post/matlab-from-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 10:26:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/post/matlab-from-python/</guid>
      <description>Nowadays the ability to write codes has become an essential skill in technical and scientific disciplines. Either you like it or not, during your studies you will find yourself doing assignments, solving equations or bigger &amp;lsquo;problems&amp;rsquo; of your projects with some sort of coding. And, if you think of going for higher studies and doing some extensive research, then writing codes is a must know skill for you.
Quite often, students will become familiar with scientific programming (note that I am not specifically refferring to CS students, focused on general purpose coding and programming) through MATLAB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exending MATLAB&#39;s tools for Negative Binomial distributions: nbin*_mu.m</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/post/matlab_toolbox_nbin_mu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/post/matlab_toolbox_nbin_mu/</guid>
      <description>Introducing a new set of functions able to deal with the common µ-k parametrization of the Negative Binomial distribution for count data.
[GitHub SOURCE CODE]
Negative Binomial Distribution Negative binomial regression is for modeling count variables, usually for over-dispersed count outcome variables.
Negative binomial regression Negative binomial regression can be used for over-dispersed count data, that is when the conditional variance exceeds the conditional mean. It can be considered as a generalization of Poisson regression since it has the same mean structure as Poisson regression and it has an extra parameter to model the over-dispersion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changelog for KMtoolbox repository - November 14, 2017</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/post/update_kmtool_repo_14november17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/post/update_kmtool_repo_14november17/</guid>
      <description> Fixed some issues on code duplication
 Created a setup file to add all the needed source files to Matlab&amp;rsquo;s path  Added some new colormap and a multiple choice of how to set up colorbar limit to improve the quality of image visualization  Added a new example dataset with heart data   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creation of a GitHub repository for lectures material</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/post/updated-lectures-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 13:49:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/post/updated-lectures-repository/</guid>
      <description> New GitHub repository with material from given lectures (Update Nov 2017) During my Ph.D. at the University of Pisa, I have had the chance to work as a Graduate Teaching Assistant for the following classes:
2017  [Ing-Inf/06]: Biomedical Imaging (6 CFU) (ITA)  Iterative reconstruction techniques for emission tomography imaging: ML-EM, OS-EM, and MAP-OSL-EM [Download slides][Lecture notes]    2016  [Ing-Inf/06]: Biomedical Imaging (6 CFU) (ITA)  Iterative reconstruction techniques for emission tomography imaging: ML-EM, OS-EM, and MAP-OSL-EM [Download slides] Introduction to kinetic modeling for emission tomography: focus on compartmental models (meaning, use, and interpratation) [Part1] [Part2]   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blind Source Separation (BSS) with the Shogun Machine Learning Toolbox</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/post/bss-shogun-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/post/bss-shogun-python/</guid>
      <description>Strongly inspired by an article by Kevin Hughes (https://github.com/kevinhughes27?tab=repositories) Today I am going to show you how we can do Blind Source Separation (BSS) using algorithms available in the Shogun Machine Learning Toolbox. What is Blind Source Separation? BSS is the separation of a set of source signals from a set of mixed signals.
My favorite example of this problem is known as the cocktail party problem where a number of people are talking simultaneously and we want to separate each persons speech so we can listen to it separately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calculating the posterior probability distribution of parameters with emcee python module</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/post/posterior-distribution-of-parameter-estimate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/post/posterior-distribution-of-parameter-estimate/</guid>
      <description>The emcee() python module emcee can be used to obtain the posterior probability distribution of parameters, given a set of experimental data. An example problem is a double exponential decay. A small amount of Gaussian noise is also added.%matplotlib inline import numpy as np import lmfit from matplotlib import pyplot as plt import corner import emcee from pylab import * ion()  x = np.linspace(1, 10, 250) np.random.seed(0) y = 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fitting theoretical model to data in python</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/post/fitting-functions-to-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/post/fitting-functions-to-data/</guid>
      <description>There are several data fitting utilities available. We will focus on two:
 scipy.optimize
 lmfit.minimize
  Using both those modules, you can fit any arbitrary function that you define and it is, also, possible to constrain given parameters during the fit. Another important aspect is that both packages come with useful diagnostic tools.
Fitting Basics The fitting we discuss here is an iterative process.
 First, we define our desired function, and calculate values given certain parameters</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to read DICOM files into Python</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/post/read_dicom_files_in_python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/post/read_dicom_files_in_python/</guid>
      <description>Dataset Dataset is the main object you will work with directly. Dataset is derived from python’s dict, so it inherits (and overrides some of) the methods of dict. In other words it is a collection of key:value pairs, where the key value is the DICOM (group,element) tag (as a Tag object, described below), and the value is a DataElement instance (also described below).
A dataset could be created directly, but you will usually get one by reading an existing DICOM file (it could be a .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PCA tutorial using scikit-learn python module</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/post/pca-tutorial-using-scikit-learn-python-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/post/pca-tutorial-using-scikit-learn-python-module/</guid>
      <description>Dimensionality Reduction: Principal Component Analysis in-depth Here we&amp;rsquo;ll explore Principal Component Analysis, which is an extremely useful linear dimensionality reduction technique.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start with our standard set of initial imports:from __future__ import print_function, division %matplotlib inline import numpy as np import matplotlib.pyplot as plt from scipy import stats # use seaborn plotting style defaults import seaborn as sns; sns.set()  Introducing Principal Component Analysis Principal Component Analysis is a very powerful unsupervised method for dimensionality reduction in data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple nonlinear least squares curve fitting in Python</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/post/python_nonlinear_least_squares/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/post/python_nonlinear_least_squares/</guid>
      <description>The problem Today we are going to test a very simple example of nonlinear least squares curve fitting using the scipy.optimize module.
%matplotlib inline import numpy as np import matplotlib.pyplot as plt from scipy.optimize import curve_fit  Create data Let&amp;rsquo;s assume we have the following points [xdata, ydata] and that we want to fit these data with the following model function using nonlinear least squares:
$F(p_1,p_2,x) = p_1\cos(p_2x) + p_2\sin(p_1x)$</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with the Academic framework for Hugo</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>The Academic framework enables you to easily create a beautifully simple personal or academic website using the Hugo static site generator.
Key features:
 Easily manage your homepage, blog posts, publications, talks, and projects Configurable widgets available for Biography, Publications, Projects, News/Blog, Talks, and Contact Need a different section? Just use the Custom widget! Write in Markdown for easy formatting and code highlighting, with LaTeX for mathematical expressions Social/academic network linking, Google Analytics, and Disqus comments Responsive and mobile friendly Simple and refreshing one page design Easy to customize  Installation  Install Hugo and create a new website by typing the following commands in your Terminal or Command Prompt app:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customizing the homepage with widgets</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/post/widgets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/post/widgets/</guid>
      <description>Homepage widgets display as sections on the homepage. They can be enabled/disabled and configured as desired. Academic has the following widgets available to use:
 About/biography Selected publications Recent publications Recent news/blog posts Projects Selected talks Recent talks Contact Custom widget (demonstrated with the teaching example)  The example site that you copied to create your site uses all the different types of widget (except talks), so you can generally just delete the widgets you don&amp;rsquo;t need and customize the parameters of the widgets you wish to keep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing content</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/post/managing-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/post/managing-content/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a brief guide to managing content with the Academic framework. Content can include publications, projects, talks, and news/blog articles. After you have read this guide about creating and managing content, you may also be interested to learn about &lt;a href=&#34;https://mscipio.github.io/post/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;writing content with Markdown, LaTeX, and Shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing content with Markdown, LaTeX, and Shortcodes</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/post/writing-markdown-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/post/writing-markdown-latex/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Content can be written using &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adam-p/markdown-here/wiki/Markdown-Cheatsheet&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/LaTeX/Mathematics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LaTeX math&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/extras/shortcodes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo Shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;. Additionally, HTML may be used for advanced formatting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>