<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Medical Imaging on Michele Scipioni</title>
    <link>https://mscipio.github.io/tags/medical-imaging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Medical Imaging on Michele Scipioni</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Michele Scipioni</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 13:49:34 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mscipio.github.io/tags/medical-imaging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Creation of a GitHub repository for lectures material</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/post/updated-lectures-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 13:49:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/post/updated-lectures-repository/</guid>
      <description> New GitHub repository with material from given lectures (Update Nov 2017) During my Ph.D. at the University of Pisa, I have had the chance to work as a Graduate Teaching Assistant for the following classes:
2017  [Ing-Inf/06]: Biomedical Imaging (6 CFU) (ITA)  Iterative reconstruction techniques for emission tomography imaging: ML-EM, OS-EM, and MAP-OSL-EM [Download slides][Lecture notes]    2016  [Ing-Inf/06]: Biomedical Imaging (6 CFU) (ITA)  Iterative reconstruction techniques for emission tomography imaging: ML-EM, OS-EM, and MAP-OSL-EM [Download slides] Introduction to kinetic modeling for emission tomography: focus on compartmental models (meaning, use, and interpratation) [Part1] [Part2]   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blind Source Separation (BSS) with the Shogun Machine Learning Toolbox</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/post/bss-shogun-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/post/bss-shogun-python/</guid>
      <description>Strongly inspired by an article by Kevin Hughes (https://github.com/kevinhughes27?tab=repositories) Today I am going to show you how we can do Blind Source Separation (BSS) using algorithms available in the Shogun Machine Learning Toolbox. What is Blind Source Separation? BSS is the separation of a set of source signals from a set of mixed signals.
My favorite example of this problem is known as the cocktail party problem where a number of people are talking simultaneously and we want to separate each persons speech so we can listen to it separately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to read DICOM files into Python</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/post/read_dicom_files_in_python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/post/read_dicom_files_in_python/</guid>
      <description>Dataset Dataset is the main object you will work with directly. Dataset is derived from python’s dict, so it inherits (and overrides some of) the methods of dict. In other words it is a collection of key:value pairs, where the key value is the DICOM (group,element) tag (as a Tag object, described below), and the value is a DataElement instance (also described below).
A dataset could be created directly, but you will usually get one by reading an existing DICOM file (it could be a .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>