<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matlab on Michele Scipioni</title>
    <link>https://mscipio.github.io/tags/matlab/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Matlab on Michele Scipioni</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Michele Scipioni</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 10:26:46 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mscipio.github.io/tags/matlab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Calling Matlab (custom) functions from Python</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/post/matlab-from-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 10:26:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/post/matlab-from-python/</guid>
      <description>Nowadays the ability to write codes has become an essential skill in technical and scientific disciplines. Either you like it or not, during your studies you will find yourself doing assignments, solving equations or bigger &amp;lsquo;problems&amp;rsquo; of your projects with some sort of coding. And, if you think of going for higher studies and doing some extensive research, then writing codes is a must know skill for you.
Quite often, students will become familiar with scientific programming (note that I am not specifically refferring to CS students, focused on general purpose coding and programming) through MATLAB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exending MATLAB&#39;s tools for Negative Binomial distributions: nbin*_mu.m</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/post/matlab_toolbox_nbin_mu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/post/matlab_toolbox_nbin_mu/</guid>
      <description>Introducing a new set of functions able to deal with the common µ-k parametrization of the Negative Binomial distribution for count data.
[GitHub SOURCE CODE]
Negative Binomial Distribution Negative binomial regression is for modeling count variables, usually for over-dispersed count outcome variables.
Negative binomial regression Negative binomial regression can be used for over-dispersed count data, that is when the conditional variance exceeds the conditional mean. It can be considered as a generalization of Poisson regression since it has the same mean structure as Poisson regression and it has an extra parameter to model the over-dispersion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MATLAB toolbox: nbin*_mu</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/project/matlab_nbin_mu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/project/matlab_nbin_mu/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changelog for KMtoolbox repository - November 14, 2017</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/post/update_kmtool_repo_14november17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/post/update_kmtool_repo_14november17/</guid>
      <description> Fixed some issues on code duplication
 Created a setup file to add all the needed source files to Matlab&amp;rsquo;s path  Added some new colormap and a multiple choice of how to set up colorbar limit to improve the quality of image visualization  Added a new example dataset with heart data   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KMtool: Kinetic Modeling Toolbox</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/project/kmtoolbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/project/kmtoolbox/</guid>
      <description>Kinetic Modeling Toolbox designed to estimate kinetic parameters from 4D PET and DCE-MRI dataset at a ROI level
[GitHub SOURCE CODE]
Updates: November 14, 2017 &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; [Check the related blog post]
&amp;gt; Fixed some issues on code duplication &amp;gt; Created a setup file to add all the needed source files to Matlab&#39;s path &amp;gt; Added some new colormap and a multiple choice of how to set up colorbar limit to improve the quality of image visualization &amp;gt; Added a new example dataset with heart data  June, 2017</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>