<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pet on Michele Scipioni</title>
    <link>https://mscipio.github.io/tags/pet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pet on Michele Scipioni</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Michele Scipioni</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 11:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mscipio.github.io/tags/pet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Changelog for KMtoolbox repository - November 14, 2017</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/post/update_kmtool_repo_14november17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/post/update_kmtool_repo_14november17/</guid>
      <description> Fixed some issues on code duplication
 Created a setup file to add all the needed source files to Matlab&amp;rsquo;s path  Added some new colormap and a multiple choice of how to set up colorbar limit to improve the quality of image visualization  Added a new example dataset with heart data   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creation of a GitHub repository for lectures material</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/post/updated-lectures-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 13:49:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/post/updated-lectures-repository/</guid>
      <description> New GitHub repository with material from given lectures (Update Nov 2017) During my Ph.D. at the University of Pisa, I have had the chance to work as a Graduate Teaching Assistant for the following classes:
2017  [Ing-Inf/06]: Biomedical Imaging (6 CFU) (ITA)  Iterative reconstruction techniques for emission tomography imaging: ML-EM, OS-EM, and MAP-OSL-EM [Download slides][Lecture notes]    2016  [Ing-Inf/06]: Biomedical Imaging (6 CFU) (ITA)  Iterative reconstruction techniques for emission tomography imaging: ML-EM, OS-EM, and MAP-OSL-EM [Download slides] Introduction to kinetic modeling for emission tomography: focus on compartmental models (meaning, use, and interpratation) [Part1] [Part2]   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CUDA-GPU kinetic modeling</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/project/gpu-lmfit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/project/gpu-lmfit/</guid>
      <description>The source code and detailed instruction about how to install and use this toolbox will be provided soon. Keep checking the website for future updates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Occiput.io</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/project/occiput/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/project/occiput/</guid>
      <description>OFFICIAL WEBSITE OF THE PROJECT
Occiput.io is an open source software for Tomographic reconstruction based on GPU computing and on Python.
The design of occiput.io makes it extremely easy to reconstruct tomographic images starting from the raw data produced by imaging systems: PET, PET-MRI and SPECT. Occiput.io is designed for GPU computing, it’s blazing fast!
To date, Occiput and the NiftyRec ray-tracer (on which Occiput is based), have been downloaded more than 12000 times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KMtool: Kinetic Modeling Toolbox</title>
      <link>https://mscipio.github.io/project/kmtoolbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mscipio.github.io/project/kmtoolbox/</guid>
      <description>Kinetic Modeling Toolbox designed to estimate kinetic parameters from 4D PET and DCE-MRI dataset at a ROI level
[GitHub SOURCE CODE]
Updates: November 14, 2017 &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; [Check the related blog post]
&amp;gt; Fixed some issues on code duplication &amp;gt; Created a setup file to add all the needed source files to Matlab&#39;s path &amp;gt; Added some new colormap and a multiple choice of how to set up colorbar limit to improve the quality of image visualization &amp;gt; Added a new example dataset with heart data  June, 2017</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>